准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
清道夫萨米
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
今天肉饼翻得可优秀了  铲铲
Nice flipping today, Spatty
你烤得真棒  架架
Great grill work, Grilly
少了你我肯定做不到  火火
And we couldn't have done it without you, Flamey
明天见
See you tomorrow
好多的垃圾
Gallopin' garbage
从来没见过蟹堡王到处都是脏东西
I've never seen the Krusty Krab
covered in this much filth
不然你说下水道居民来开大会能咋样
What do you expect from a Sewer Dwellers' convention
下水道居民  本地396号
讲餐桌礼仪吗
table manners?
好了
All right
你也待得差不多了
You've had enough
可以不用回下水道去
You don't have to go back to the sewer
但就是不准待在这
but you can't stay here
我们关门了
We're closed
走之前  把蟹堡王打扫干净
Well, make sure this place is spotless before you leave
遵命  蟹老板
Aye, aye, Mr. Krabs
遵命了
Ay-yi-yi
这下得通宵打扫了
This is going to take me all night
马上开始扫吧
Well, I'd better get started
真希望能有个朋友帮忙清理干净
I wish I had a friend to help me clean this place up
好强的东风
Strong wind coming in from the east
我敢打赌  更确切地说
More specifically, I'd wager
吹的是东北风
we're coming in from the northeast
谁在说话
Who said that?
是我  先生
I did, Gov'ner
拖拖  刚刚的着陆
Moppy, that landing
从各方面来说都切实可行
was perfectly practical in every way
你是谁啊
Who are you?
我是清道夫萨米
Why, I'm Sammy Suckerfish
也正是快乐清洁工
the jolly janitor I am, I am
风中传来的消息说
And the word on the wind is
你需要找帮手打扫
you need a little cleaning
还真是
Boy, do I
你好啊  拖拖
Hiya, Moppy
天啊  快看看那片可爱又可恨的脏污
Blimey, will you take a gander
at all that lovely ruddy filth?
要先清理哪里呢
What should we clean first?
我向来都会先清理餐厅的眼睛
Well, I always like to start with the eyes of the eatery
也就是窗户
that meaning the windows
我准备好了
I'm ready
那些东西可以收起来了  老朋友
You can put those away, me old mucker
可那样还怎么擦窗户呢
But how are we going to wash the windows?
我来告诉你吧
Well, I'll tell ya
有的清洁工清洁只会用板刷
There are janitors who only clean with brushes
还有的用抹布或扫把
Others use a rag or cloth or broom
但是归根结底
But when all is said and done
我发现用舌头最好
I find it best to use me tongue
失陪一下  让我舔舔这房间
So excuse me while I lick this room
你也试试舔舔看
Now give your tongue a go
好
OK
恶心
Yuck
萨米  嘴里味道太难受了
Sammy, that tastes horrible
那现在呢
How about now?
现在嘴里感觉不出味道了
Now I can't taste anything
鼻子没味  嘴里也会没味
If you can't smell it, you can't taste it
继续唱吧
Back to singing
脏污快快舔干净
Lick all the dirt up lickety-split
脏污统统舔干净
Lick all the dirt up, every bit
舔干净窗户  舔干净门
Lick all the windows, lick all the doors
舔完天花板  又舔地板
Lick up the ceiling, lick up the floors
舔干净脏污  就这么定
Lick all the dirt up, that's the plan
脏污吐进垃圾桶
Spit out the dirt into the can
这里的脏污舔干净
Lick all the dirt up in the place
脸上的脏污舔干净
Lick all the dirt up off your face
我抹布再也无用武之地
I'll never use a cloth or rag again
舌头刷刷拖拖都特干净
My tongue can now out-clean or brush or mop
他海绵宝宝  我萨米
He's SpongeBob and I'm Sammy
绝不用皮革清理
We refuse to use a shammy
我们要一直舔个不停
We're licking it up and we will never stop
美味
Yum
老螃蟹小气  章鱼哥好臭
"Krabs is cheap, Squidward smells"
确实
It's true
章鱼哥味道好极了
Squidward smells great
可是要怎么清掉这堆涂鸦
But how do we get this graffiti off?
有些污渍十分顽固
Some stains are so tough
得用一点点神奇皂粉对付
they need a little-a bit-a magic soap
一  二
One, two
涂鸦变
graffiti, boo
他们要清死我们
They're gonna clean us to death--
还是用我们自个的舌头
with our own tongues
没必要害怕
Not necessarily
涂鸦变
Graffiti boo
万岁
Hooray
成功了
We did it
全都清干净了
We cleaned everything
这里肯定还有地方得清理  老兄
I'm sure there's still more cleaning
around here to do, love
闻出脏污吧  乖拖拖
Sniff out the dirt, Moppy old girl
我的小眼睛看到了这间肮脏房间
I spy with my little eye this filthy room
不行
No, no
蟹老板不准外人进他办公室
Mr. Krabs doesn't like anybody in his office
你的蟹老板肯定不介意
I'm sure your Mr. Krabs wouldn't mind
我们帮他整理一下
if we tidied up a bit
墙上都是杂物
These walls are chock-full of clutter
可是萨米  那都是蟹老板的私有财产
But Sammy, that's Mr. Krabs's private property
不好意思  小子
Excuse me, lad
萨米  那样会有大麻烦的
Sammy, we're gonna get in big trouble
别清保险柜啊
Not the safe
不要
No
别清秘密配方啊
Not the secret formula
秘密配方
Secret formula?
你是说这个吗
You mean this?
秘密配方
清道夫萨米
Sammy Suckerfish
马上把秘密配方吐出来
you spit out that secret formula this instant
我都说过了  我一清理就停不下来
I told you, I can't stop cleaning
萨米
Sammy
举起手来  痞老板
Hands up, Plankton
我已经包围你了
I got you surrounded--
什么
wha?
萨米  住嘴啊
Sammy, stop it
不要
No
蟹老板  真对不起
Mr. Krabs, I'm so sorry
我叫过他住嘴了的
I told him to stop
站一边去  小子
Step aside, boy-o
我知道是怎么一回事
I know what's going on here
晚上好  先生
Evening, Gov'ner
把你的英国佬假脑袋摘下来  痞老板
Take off that phony British head, Plankton
你谁都骗不到
You're not fooling anyone
你肯定就在里面  痞老板
I know you're in there, Plankton
马上给我滚出来
Come on, get out of there already
海之霸
小点声
Keep it down
咱这边一大早还得偷秘密配方呢
Some people have to
steal the secret formula in the morning
等下
Wait
如果他不是痞老板  那他是谁
If he's not Plankton, then who is he?
他
He--
他是个神奇清洁工
he's a magical janitor
还刚舔走了你保险柜门和里面的秘方
that licked off your safe door
and the secret formula with it
秘密配方
什么
What?
还回来
Give that back
没关系  先生们
No worries, gents
那个保险柜可干净了
That safe is as clean as a whistle
对吧  拖拖
Right, Moppy?
隆重介绍小拖拖
Introducing the Moppettes
脏污快快舔干净
Lick all the dirt up lickety-split
脏污统统舔干净
Lick all the dirt up, every bit
舔干净窗户  舔干净门
Lick all the windows, lick all all the doors
秘密配方还是印在他舌头上
He's still got the secret formula stuck to his tongue
我一定要把秘方抢回来
I've gotta get the formula back
我也是
Me, too
你想得美  谢尔顿
Oh, no, you don't, Sheldon
滚出去
Get out
秘方抢不回来  我也会完蛋的
I've got a stake in this, too, you know
好吧
OK
暂时休战
Temporary truce
拦住那根舌头
Stop that tongue
等等
Wait
什么
What?
加快速度
Double time
脏污快快舔干净
Lick all the dirt up lickety-split
脏污统统舔干净
Lick all the dirt up, every bit
舔干净窗户  舔干净门
Lick all the windows, lick all the doors
舔完天花板  又舔地板
Lick up the ceiling, lick up the floors
舔干净脏污  就这么定
Lick all the dirt up, that's the plan
脏污吐进垃圾桶
Spit out the dirt into the can
这里的脏污舔干净
Lick all the dirt up in the place
脸上的脏污舔干净
Lick all the dirt up off your face
别那么用力
Not so hard
脏污快快
Lick all the dirt up--
抱歉  萨米
Sorry, Sammy
我们需要你的舌头
but we need your tongue
早说过了  我一清理就停不下来
I told you, I can't stop cleaning
萨米  你身上有污渍
Sammy, you have smudges all over you
污渍
A smudge?
我身上
On me?
那就要来洗澡了  对吧
Well, then, I suppose it's bath time, innit?
秘密配方
The secret formula
很好玩吧  海绵宝宝
That was fun, eh, Spongey?
再见了  可别说我什么都没给过你
So long, and don't say I never give you nothing
秘密配方
秘方
The formula
谢了  先生
Thanks, Gov'ner
笑一个  秘密配方
Say cheese, secret formula
清理掉那个肮脏小坏蛋
Clean that dirty little scoundrel
我开玩笑的
I'm just kidding
希望你能明白
I hope it's clear
为什么关门后不让陌生人进来  小子
why we don't let strangers in after closing time, boy-o
清楚明白  蟹老板
Yes, sir, Mr. Krabs
干净又明了
Crystal clear
神厨大联盟
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
没错  先生
Yes, sir
我发现咱特别需要找个新大厨
I'm well aware that we need a new super chef
蟹堡王
给我们新开的体育场大餐厅下厨
for the big, new stadium restaurant
我这边已经发现了三个潜在的人选
I found three potential candidates
只要再找一个就行了
and I just need one more
那人必须活力四射
someone with pizzazz
能不能别活力了  好好做蟹黄堡
Will you cut the pizzazz and finish the order?
跟你说  我先挂了
Listen, I gotta go
老兄
Hey, buddy
你刚刚的厨艺太神了
That's some mighty fancy cooking
那是我的餐吗
Is that my order?
里面有什么瑕疵吗
Is there anything wrong with it?
竟然会问里面有没有瑕疵
Is there anything wrong, he says
根本就是完美无瑕啊
There's only everything right with it
与其在这家小破店上班
What are you doing here in this greasy dump
不如来大联盟当神厨明星吧
when you could be a culinary superstar
in the big leagues?
谁是你老板
Who's your manager?
谁啊
Who?
蟹老板是我老板
Mr. Krabs is my manager
吵什么吵
What's all that rumpus in here?
这小丑鱼是哪位
Who is this clownfish?
我这小丑鱼要让你发大财
This clownfish is gonna make you a very wealthy crab
神厨体育场大餐厅
Culinary Stadium Restaurant?
什么东西
What's that?
是个全新又大胆的概念
It's a bold new concept
神厨体育场
我们把棒球场改造成了餐厅
We've converted a baseball stadium into a restaurant
可以同时为上千名食客服务
serving thousands of food fans at the same time
所以要付你多少钱才能把这位新手
So how much to take this greenhorn
这只菜鸟  这艘身上全是洞的小船
this rookie, this dinghy full of holes
从你蟹爪中带走呢
off of your claws?
看看他
Look at him
领带都被食物弄脏了
Food stains on his tie
太糟糕了
Deplorable
才不糟糕
Not deplorable--
可好吃了
delicious
我绝对不会跟我员工分开
I could never part ways with me--
抱歉刚刚胡言乱语了
Pardon my vapors
可是蟹老板  我不想离开蟹堡王啊
But Mr. Krabs, I don't want to leave the Krusty Krab
真不是我想不让你留下  小子
Yeah, far be it from me to hold you back, boy-o
不过看在这么多钱的情况嘛
By the looks of this legal tender
很明显你命中注定要追求远大前程
it's obvious you're destined
for bigger and better things
我们快走吧
Let's get out of here
小子
Hey, kid
加油吧  大人物
Go get 'em, hotshot
惊艳大伙儿
Knock 'em dead
选拔厨房
好了  你们这群小厨子
OK, you lowly hash slingers
这里是选拔厨房
This is the tryout kitchen
你们四个要互相竞争厨艺
The four of you
will compete cooking against each other
期间会一个接一个地淘汰
You'll be eliminated one by one
最后只会有一位厨子能留下
until there's only one of you left standing
有且只有那个厨子
That person and only that person
可以为全场下厨
will cook for the whole stadium
并且荣获神厨头衔
and receive the title of super chef
淘汰会有什么下场
What happens when you're eliminated?
就要上高速公路卖脏水热狗
You'll be selling dirty water hot dogs on the freeway
高速入口
好像很好玩
Looks like fun
你好
Hello
我是海绵宝宝
My name is SpongeBob
握个手吧
Put her there
卷卷手指薯条
Curly finger fries
快点开始了  你们这群菜鸟厨子
Let's go, go, go, you goofy gourmets
肉汤和食材都提供给大家了
You got your broth, and you got your ingredients
我要品尝到独一无二的汤
I want to taste a soup that's unique
而且还要有非凡的味道
with a flavor that's singular
开始下厨
Let's get cooking
谢了
Thanks
哎哟喂
Aw, gee
看来你调料都没固定好啊
Looks like you ain't got no fixings for mix-ins
这样很过分
That's not fair
要听浪漫晚宴音乐吗
Some romantic dinner music?
知道你汤里缺什么吗
You know what your soup needs?
要加点粗纤维
A little roughage
我来帮你搞定
Let me "nail" it for you
钉
只剩十秒了
Ten seconds left
怎么办
What do I do?
看看他
Look at him
领带都被食物弄脏了
Food stains on his tie
我的领带
My tie
泡一泡
Dunk, dunk
还可以
Not bad
不可以有钉子
Nails are unacceptable
你出局了
You're out
还可以
Not bad
不好也不坏
Not good, but not bad
太棒了
Excellent
清淡提神  里面还混有人造纤维
Light, refreshing with just a hint of rayon
本轮海绵获胜
This round goes to the sponge
听好了  你们这群菜鸟
Listen up, you gruff guppies
下一关是披萨
The next challenge is pizza
我要的披萨必须无与伦比  意想不到
I want a pizza that's extraordinary, unanticipated
出人意料
from left field--
不许有钉子
and no nails
兄弟  之前的事真是抱歉
Look, buddy, I'm sorry about before
我来补偿一下你吧
Let me make it up to you
我用我妈的秘方特制了这份披萨面团
I've made this special pizza dough
from me old mother's recipe
请你收下吧
I'd like you to have it
太谢谢了
Much obliged
有薄荷味
Minty
你就这么喜欢钉子是吗
So you like nails, do you?
竟敢偷我奶酪
Stealing my cheese, huh?
对付你这种小虾米  我自有办法
I know just what to do with shrimps like you
那只虾怎么了
What happened to the shrimp?
应该是抗压能力太弱了吧
I guess some folks can't handle the pressure
老龟  到你了
Turtle, you're up
没钉子的事我怎么说的
What did I say about no nails?
你出局了
You're out
我跟你杠上了
It had to be you
死都要找你报仇雪恨
I'll get back at you if it's the last thing I do
形状独特
Unusual shape
有薄荷  热带浆果
Hints of mint, tropical berry
肉桂
cinnamon
这又是什么味道
But what's this flavor?
原来是这样
That's it
虾
Shrimp
我就爱往披萨加虾
I love shrimp on pizza
选拔赛结束了
The competition is over
看来你打出全垒打了  海绵
Looks like you hit a home run, sponge
欢迎加入大联盟
Welcome to the big leagues
连从未有过的梦想居然都能实现
Even the dreams that you've never had can come true
神厨体育场
欢迎光临神厨体育场  食客们
Welcome to the Culinary Stadium, food fans
马上就要开始下厨了
The cooking is about to begin
各位食客  请大家热烈欢迎
Food fans, will you please give a warm welcome
新任神厨  海绵宝宝
to our new super chef, SpongeBob SquarePants?
海绵宝宝
就你了  冠军
That's you, champ
上场吧
You're on
小子
Hey, kid
一鸣惊人吧
Knock it out of the park
开始下厨
Let's cook
首先要做的是  焦糖海草
First up, caramelized kelp
青酱珊瑚  以及巧克力烤藻
pesto coral, and grilled chocolate algae
菜鸟迎来了个开门红
The rookie is off to a great start
他表现十分出彩
He's showing excellent form
看看那小子的胳膊
Look at the arm on that kid
油炸海香蕉  金箔面包
Fried sea bananas, the gold flake breadsticks
培根卷豆角
twigs in a blanket
海绵宝宝下厨绝对一流
SpongeBob is handling all the orders
like a true champion
就说我会找他报仇的吧
I told him I'd get him back
这地方怎么没桌子
Why are there no tables up here?
餐桌只给下面高级区的阔佬用
The tables with food are for the wealthy moneybags
down below in the premium section
就只能眼睁睁看别人吃了吗
We only get to watch 'em eat?
没错
I know
是不是很棒啊
Isn't it wonderful?
快给我
Give me that
技巧如此之高超灵活
Such skill, such agility
但他能否跟上速度呢
But can he keep up the pace?
菜鸟的点餐单越积越多了
The orders are piling up for our rookie
看来我们的小子有麻烦了
Looks like our boy is in trouble
厨房已经满负荷了
All food bases are loaded
你在干什么
What are you doing?
给海绵宝宝送点餐单
I'm giving SpongeBob an order
他有它稳赢
I know he can win with
我先猜猜看
Let me guess
蟹黄堡
Krabby patties
果不其然
Typical
看来神厨接到了一项特别订单
Looks like our chef has a special order, folks
等一下
Wait a minute
这美食好像有些俗
That doesn't look like gourmet food
暂停
Time-out
你应该做的是高级菜
You're supposed to be cooking high-class cuisine
不是快餐
not fast food
好吧  谢谢你给我机会
Yeah, well, thanks for the opportunity
不过我还是宁愿留在蟹堡联盟
but I like it better in the Krusty leagues
我弃赛
I forfeit
这年头的小孩子
These kids today
还消极比赛了
No respect for the game
小子
Hey, kid
你一定会爆红
You're blowing up big-time
听见没
Don't you hear 'em?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
快出场
Go out there
鞠出最后一躬
Take your final bow
他到底哪去了
Where the heck does he go?
好耶
Yeah
感谢
Thank you
我们的小子回归了
Our boy's come back to us
我不是早说你会爆红的吗
Didn't I tell you you were blowing up?
还真是  小子
You sure did, kid